Guide to the U.S. Census 2000 Advertising Files, 2000-2002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
U.S. Census 2000 Advertising Files 2000-2002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
U.S. Census Bureau.
Extent: About 300 items 3.0 linear feet
The U.S. Census Bureau conducts a nationwide census every 10 years. Census 2000 sought to count and classify a record number of the American population, emphasizing the changing demographics of the country. This collection was donated to the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, & Marketing History by Sybil F. Stershic, a member of the Census Advisory Committee of Professional Associations for Census 2000. The collection includes a Census 2000 advertising binder, several informational and promotional posters, a partnership informational kit, and two special reports. There are also two VHS tapes with advertisements from the Census 2000 campaign. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, & Marketing History.
RL.00218
Language: Materials in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to researchersg.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Gift, 2008 (2008-0247), 3.0 lin. ft.
Historical Note
The U.S. Census Bureau conducts a nationwide census every 10 years. Census 2000 sought to count and classify a record number of the American population, emphasizing the changing demographics of the country. This collection was donated to the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, & Marketing History by Sybil F. Stershic, a member of the Census Advisory Committee of Professional Associations for Census 2000.
Collection Overview
The collection includes a Census 2000 advertising binder, several informational and promotional posters, a partnership informational kit, and two special reports. There are also two VHS tapes with advertisements from the Census 2000 campaign. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, & Marketing History.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Advertising; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, & Marketing History.; U.S. Census Bureau; United States -- Population -- Statistics; United States -- Census, 22nd, 2000; Posters; Videocassettes
Contents of Collection
- Accession (2008-0247), 3 Boxes
  The collection includes a Census 2000 advertising binder, several informational and promotional posters, a partnership informational kit, and two special reports. There are also two VHS tapes with advertisements from the Census 2000 campaign.
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Employment pamphlets
  - Demographic Trends in the 20th Century
  - Mapping Census 2000: The Geography of U.S. Diversity
  - Partnership Report, Vol. 1
  - The Longest Continuous Scientific Project in American Democracy: U.S. Census 2000
  - U.S. Census 2000 Info Kit
  - Book of Ads, 2000 (Box 2)
    - A binder with advertisements encouraging participation in the 2000 Census written in numerous languages and targeting minorities and ethnic groups.
  - Posters (Box 3)
    - Guam
    - Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands (CNMI)
    - American Samoa
    - Census 2000: Don't Be Missed!
    - We Have Always Protected Our Traditions. (Native American)
    - Keep It Real (African American)
    - No INS, No FBI, No CIA, No IRS (Spanish)
    - Your Answers are Private: It's the Law